字幕來源：筱宸葭@-=TLF字幕組=-
■
后期：waterzzd
你有什么打算
What's your resolution?
-我打算減肥  -可你是墨西哥人
-I'm going to cut carbs. -Aren't you Mexican?
奶奶做的東西你都不能吃了
You can't eat nothin' Grandma makes.
養成一種習慣只要30天
It only takes 30 days to form a habit
之后就會變成第二天性
and then it becomes second nature.
根據真實事件改編
-誰說的  -奧普拉
-Who says that? -Oprah.
奧普拉  (著名脫口秀主持人)
OK. Oprah cool now?
你有什么打算
What's yours?
我不想再販賣大麻
I want to quit selling trees.
弗魯特韋爾地鐵站  2009年新年
加州  奧克蘭市  凌晨2:15
-為什么不讓我們走  -我不知道
-Why are we still here? -I don't know. . .
看那個拍照的家伙
Look at that man taking pictures and shit.
坐下  閉嘴
Sit down! Shut the fuck up!
-嘿  -別動手
-Hey! -Hey, come on, man!
別動手
Come on, now!
注意你的身份
Protect and serve! Protect and serve!
-別動手  -別動手
-Come on, man. -Come on now, y'all!
-真的  -你這個黑鬼
-Really? -Bitch-ass nigger, huh?
你這個黑鬼
Bitch-ass nigger, aren't ya?
這里有情況
Hey, that's hella fucked up!
有情況
That's fucked up!
放了他  搞什么
Let him go! What the fuck?
等等  等等
Hold up, hold up.
加州  海沃德  2008年新年前夕  上午12:10
蘇菲婭  我已經忍很久了
Fuck, Sophina.I've been holding, how long?
我不知道
I don't know.
每次你碰我
Every time you touch me,
我都會想到你和那個賤人親熱
all I can think about is how you was touching that bitch.
你老是揪著這事不放
I'll never hear the end of that shit.
你知道嗎
You know what?
你說的對  去吧
You're right. Go.
我去干嘛
What I gotta do? Hm?
我就和她搞過一次
Fucked with her that one time.
是你被抓到一次
Nah. You got caught...one time.
別跟我說
Are you gonna sit here and tell me
那是你第一次和那個賤人鬼混
that was the first time you kicked it with that bitch?
你之前沒見過她
You ain't never seen her before that, huh?
都過去了
That shit's over with.
我要的是你和T
All I want is you...and T.
永遠
Forever.
你說永遠是什么意思
What you mean, forever?
等下你就知道了
Let me show you.
爸爸
Daddy?
-快去  -她叫的是你
-Go help. -Mm-mm. She's asking for you.
-怎么了  -我睡不著
-What's up? -I can't sleep.
睡不著
You can't sleep.
你想和爸爸媽媽一起睡嗎
You want to sleep in here with Mommy and Daddy?
-嗯  -好
-Mm-hm. -Mm-hm.
T  你怎么這么不懂事  幾點了
T, you know better than that. What time is it?
下半夜了
It's after midnight.
(發送短信給媽媽:生日快樂)
媽媽  今天我能帶兩份果干嗎
Mommy? Can I have two fruit snacks today?
不行  你可以多帶一個蘋果
No, you can have an extra apple if you want.
-媽媽  -別跟我爭
-But, Mommy...-Don't argue with me, T.
太早了
It's too early.
-我們得給車加油  -剩下的油夠開到幼兒園
-Oh, come on, we have to go get gas. -We got enough to get us there.
噓
Shh!
-早上好  塔蒂阿娜  -早上好  史黛西太太
-Good morning, Tatiana. -Good morning, Mrs. Stacy.
-你好嗎  奧斯卡  -很好  你好嗎
-How you doin' today, Oscar? -I'm doing good, you?
看到沒  我說了油夠了
See? Told you we'd make it.
你回家睡覺嗎
You're gonna go home and sleep, right?
我還有事  為晚上準備東西
Nah, I'm gonna head up to the job. Get some stuff for tonight.
我死也不愿休息日來這
I'd rather die than come here on my day off.
我們會去舊金山吧
We're gonna go to 'Frisco, right?
看煙花
See the fireworks?
當然會去
Yeah. We'll do that.
-好  -好
-Cool. -Cool.
那我下車了
All right, let me get in here.
你的脖子好咸
Mm...The back of your neck is all salty.
-不說拜拜  -拜拜
-Are you gonna say bye? -Bye.
我也愛你
Love you, too!
(呼叫媽媽)
喂
Hello?
再問一次  你今天生日也要去上班嗎
Last shot,right here.You sure you want to work on your birthday?
我過來接你去慶祝吧
I'm gonna come get you. Let's go celebrate.
聽著很誘人
Well, as tempting as that sounds,
但這兒要是沒我會大亂的
this place would be a mess without me today.
好吧  要我買一些螃蟹嗎
OK. You still want me to pick up a couple crabs for later, right?
好啊  你能買些...
Yes, and could you pick up a couple of. . .
你在開車
Are you driving?
-是的  -戴耳機了沒
-Yeah. -Are you wearing your earpiece?
-戴了  -別騙我
-Yeah. -Don't lie to me.
等一下
All right, hold on.
-喂  -現在戴上了
-Hello? -Is it on now?
戴上了
Yeah.
你幫我買一些蝦米
OK. Yeah. Get me a couple of packets of dried shrimp.
到時給你錢
Stop by on your way and I'll give you the money.
錢的事你不用管
Don't worry about that.
我晚上會給你錢
All right, then, I'll pay you back tonight.
不用了  媽媽
Come on, Ma. Don't trip.
今天是你生日
You ain't payin' for nothin' on your birthday.
我要忙了
OK, I need to run on in here, baby.
-晚上見  -好
-I'll see you later tonight? -Yeah.
-我愛你  -我也愛你
-I love you. -I love you, too.
謝謝
Thank you.
-奧斯卡  -你好嗎
-Osc, what's good boy? -What's good with you, bruh?
-老樣子  你找埃米  -他在嗎
-Yeah, same shit. You looking for Emi? -Yeah, he here?
今天早些時候見過他  不知道現在他在哪
I seen that nigger earlier today, bruh. I don't know where he at now.
-對了  給我來些螃蟹  -我想起來了
-Oh bruh, came to get some crabs, too. -Crab...Ah shit, that's right.
-今天是媽媽生日  -對啊
-It's Ma's birthday today? -Yeah.
不好意思  我忘了  替我跟她說生日快樂
My bad, I forgot. Tell her I said happy birthday.
-你怎么不自己去跟她說  -我今晚走不開
-Why don't you come tell her yourself? -I can't do it tonight, boy.
-我另有安排  -少來了
-I gotta bust some moves. -You ain't bustin' shit.
新年跨年有什么安排
What's good for the countdown though?
去舊金山看煙花
You know, 'Frisco, fireworks, the whole shit.
-明白嗎  -明白
-Feelin' me? -Yeah, yeah.
要幫忙嗎
Need help?
我要一磅...
Uh, yeah. Can I get a pound of your. . .
我能看看鰨目魚長什么樣嗎
Can you show me what your sole looks like?
可以
Yeah.
-鰨目魚  -好
-Sole. -Uh...OK.
我能看看鯰魚嗎
What about your catfish? Can I see that?
-這就是鯰魚  -我想做炸魚
-Yeah, cat. -OK, I want to do like, a fish fry.
這種魚可以嗎
Are these ones good to fry?
開什么玩笑  是魚都可以
What the fuck, man. It's fish. You can fry all of it.
稍等一下
Right...Just give me a second.
你要給媽媽買什么
Yeah. What do you need for Moms, bruh?
我要三個丹金尼斯大海蟹  去后面拿
Let me get three Dungeness Crab. From the back, bruh.
要肥一點的  別耍我
Fat ones, too. Don't try and play me.
新年晚餐準備做炸魚
So, you're having a fish fry for New Year's or something?
差不多吧
Uh, yeah. Something like that.
我在這上班  我可以幫你
Oh, I work here. I can help you figure it out.
今天我休息
It's my day off.
我想在去舊金山前給一個朋友做頓飯
Um...Well, I'm cooking for a friend tonight before we go to the city,
他喜歡吃南方風味的炸魚
and he loves fried fish, like Southern style. . .
-南方風味  他是黑人  -不  他是白人
-Southern. Sounds like he's black. -Oh, no, he's white.
他應該認識不少黑人
But he knows a lot of black people, I guess.
噢
Uh-huh.
我自己完全沒頭緒
I don't know what I got myself into.
(呼叫邦妮奶奶)
-喂  -奶奶
-Hello? -Grandma?
奧斯卡  你好嗎
Oscar, how you doin', baby?
-我在上班  -你在上班
-I'm at work and I got this...-You're at work?
-是的  奶奶  -拜拜
-Yeah, Grandma. -Bye.
不不不  奶奶  今天我休息
No, no, no, Grandma. It's my day off, all right?
-我在為晚餐買東西  -不好意思
-I'm shopping for the party tonight. -Oh, l'm sorry, baby.
我以為你在玩手機
I thought you were playing on the phone.
沒有  奶奶  我這有位顧客
Oh no, Grandma. But I do have this customer here.
她想做炸魚  但是不知道怎么做
She wants to have a fish fry, but she don't know how.
你能告訴她怎么做嗎
You think you can tell her everything she needs to know?
沒問題  她想做什么炸魚
Oh, no problem, baby. What kind of fish does she want to fry?
奶奶  她也不知道
Grandma, she don't know.
她不知道自己要做什么炸魚
She don't know what kind of fish she wants to fry?
是的  奶奶
Nah, Grandma, nah.
讓她接電話
Put her on the phone.
-她怎么稱呼  -邦妮奶奶
-What's her name? -Grandma Bonnie.
你好  邦妮奶奶
Hi, Grandma Bonnie.
埃米來了
There's Emi's right there, bruh.
我叫凱蒂  你好
...Katie. It's nice to meet you.
-早啊  埃米  -奧斯卡  什么事
-Hey, good morning, Emi. -Oscar. What's going on?
給我媽媽的生日準備東西
Trying to pick up some stuff for my Mom's birthday.
東西都買齊了吧
Hope you found everything you need.
我想跟你說幾句
Yeah, I just want to talk to you for a second.
現在不行  節假日忙死了
It's a little nuts right now,holiday and all.
我想談談我工作的事
Look, I want to talk about my job.
-職位已經滿了  -埃米
-The position's been filled. -Look, look, Emi
我真的很需要這份工作
Look, I really need this job, all right?
過去我的處境很糟  我現在想重新開始
I was going through some shit before trying to get back on my feet,
你知道我需要這份工作
you feel me, but...I need this.
你可以讓我每周一班  我沒意見
You can start me off with one shift a week or whatever, I'll be here.
付我一半工資就行
Work me 40 hours, only pay me for 20. . .
我已經雇了別人
Dude, I hired somebody else.
我如果讓你回來  就得開除別的員工
For me to bring you back, that means I have to let someone else go.
從沒遲到過一次的員工
Someone who's never showed up late once.
不好意思  我喜歡你這人
I'm sorry, I like you, man. . .
我需要這份工作
I need this fuckin' job, bruh.
你想我販毒嗎
You want me sellin' dope, bruh?
奧斯卡
Oscar. . .
要我在外面等你忙完再談嗎
You need me outside waiting for you to get done, bruh?
你自己保重
You take care of yourself.
嘿
Hey!
我現在成專家了
I'm an expert now.
看來怎么做你都清楚了
See you got everything you need.
都清楚了  謝謝你
I've got everything, thank you.
不用謝
No problem.
-還給你  -噢
-Here you go. -Oh.
我叫凱蒂
I'm Katie, by the way.
-奧斯卡  -新年快樂
-Oscar. -Happy New Year.
-新年快樂  -怎么樣
-Happy New Year. -What's up, bruh?
-埃米人很好  -他讓你回來工作
-Emi was good. -He put you back on?
-下個星期開始  -那就好
-Starting next week. -That's what's up.
保重  我們今晚慶祝
Take it easy, man. We celebrating tonight.
-別遲到  -不用擔心
-Can you not be late? -Don't even worry about that, man.
-記得接電話  注意安全  -好的
-Just answer your phone. Be safe, bruh. -All right. Yep.
(香蒂來電)
-喂  -笨蛋  你好嗎
-Hello? -Hey chump, what's up?
-你在干嘛  -剛下班回來
-What are you doin'? -Just got back in from the job.
我以為今天你休息
l thought you was off today?
-是的  -你打給媽媽沒
-I am. -You call Mom yet?
-打了  你呢  -打了
-Yeah, did you? -Yeah.
我有一些好消息和壞消息
But I got some good news and some bad news.
先說壞消息
Gimme the bad news first.
我這個月的租金還沒湊齊
I'm gonna need some help with rent this month.
-差多少  -300塊
-How much? -Like, 300.
我過幾周就還你
But l can get you back in a couple of weeks.
可以  好消息是什么
OK, so what's the good news?
-我今晚得加班  -不是吧  香蒂
-I'm doing overtime tonight. -Come on, Chantay.
我必須加班  再說媽媽會理解的
l gotta do it. Plus, Moms understands.
替我給媽媽買張卡片并寫好祝福語
But I need you to get her a card for me and sign it, all right?
沒問題
All right.
別買有白人的那種
Osc, don't get me no fake-ass card with no white people on it.
要黑人卡片
I want a black card.
-沒問題  -好的
-All right, I got you. -All right.
-我愛你  -我也愛你  搗蛋鬼
-I love you, all right? -Love you too, screw up.
拜拜
Whatever, bye.
(呼叫馬庫斯)
什么事  奧斯卡
What's up with it, Osc?
你好嗎  老兄  昨晚是我的錯
What's good with it, bruh? My bad about last night.
你還想要嗎
Still trying to get that?
不過我不會去那邊  我一整天都在鎮上
Hey, I'm not out that way though. I'm gonna be in the town all day.
沒事  我可以來找你
It's cool, I can come to you, bruh.
那好  我們在80號公路海邊碰頭
All right, meet me over here by the water. Right off the 80.
大概一小時到
Gimme about an hour.
-沒問題  -行
-All right, bet that. -Bet.
就這個
Yeah.
嘿
Hey. . .
好狗狗
What's up, boy?
What's up, boy? What's up?
(發送短信給蘇菲婭:要我中午過去嗎)
(蘇菲婭:已經取了)
嘿嘿嘿  停車
Hey! Hey! Hey, slow down!
停車  混蛋
Hey! Hey! Slow down! You bitch motherfucker!
停車
Slow down!
怎么樣
Hi. What's up, bruh?
怎么樣  沒事的
What's up, bruh? It's all right, bruh.
沒事的
It's all right.
It's all right, bruh.
沒事的  還有我呢
It's all right, bruh...You with me, bruh?
堅持住
Come on, bruh. . .
Come on.
誰來幫幫我
Somebody help!
格蘭特
Grant, come on.
給我看看你的手  耳朵
All right, let me see your hands...ears. . .
圣昆丁聯邦監獄  加州  圣拉斐爾  2007年新年前夕
頭發  嘴巴
. . .your hair...inside your mouth.
轉身
All right, turn around.
彎腰  蹲下
Bend over, squat.
可以了
All right, you're good.
-孩子  -媽媽
-Hey baby. -Hey Mama.
生日快樂
Happy birthday.
你臉怎么了
What happened to your face?
你今天氣色不錯
You look nice today.
塔蒂阿娜昨晚去看你了嗎
My girls came to see you last night?
-我們一起玩了棋盤游戲  -你一定會讓她贏
-We played board games. -I bet y'all let her win, too.
-當然  -太弱了
-Of course. -Y'all hella weak for that.
她沒這么容易贏我
She'll get no easy wins around me.
-嗯  -怎么了
-Mm. -What?
還記得前陣子你帶回來的爆米花嗎
Remember that microwave popcorn you bought a while back?
-很好吃  -是的
-Hella good. -Yeah.
我把爆米花倒進碗里
While I was putting it in the bowl,
塔蒂阿娜站在那瞪著我
Tatiana just standing there,staring up at me,
好像她想要什么
looking like she wanted something.
后來呢  說啊
OK, then what? Come on, Ma.
她問我  外婆  有高脂奶油嗎
She says, "Grandma, do we have any dark butter?"
高脂奶油
Dark...What's dark butter?
我想她可能在美食頻道看到過
I'm thinking maybe she watched Food Network or something.
我說  孩子  什么是高脂奶油
I said, "Sweetheart, what's dark butter?"
她說  爸爸帶我去看《機器人瓦力》時
And she said, "Well, when my daddy took me to see Wall-E,
他點的低脂奶油
he asked for light butter.
所以這次我要嘗嘗高脂奶油
So now I want to try some dark butter this time."
-她很聰明  -這是你媽媽
-She too smart...-This Moms right here?
-她也是小偷  -你說她什么
-She a snitch, too? -What the fuck you say about my moms?
-去你媽的  -要不是這有警衛
-Fuck you and this bitch. -Talking tough with these guards.
如果在外面我揍扁你
I'm gonna see your bitch-ass on the outside.
-帕爾馬黑鬼  -混蛋
-Bitch-ass Palma Ceia nigger. -Bitch-ass motherfucker.
-奧斯卡  -關你屁事
-Oscar...-Fuck DGF!
-有事嗎  -去你媽的
-Is there a problem in here? -Oh, fuck you!
-有事嗎  -沒事
-Is there a problem here? -No, we good.
現在沒事
Yeah, we good for now.
沒事
Yeah.
你媽的
Yeah, fucked up. . .
冷靜點
Calm down.
奧斯卡
Oscar.
你臉怎么了
What happened to your face?
高脂奶油
Dark butter. . .
她很注意別人說什么
She always listenin'.
她太聰明了
Too damn smart for her own good.
幼兒園的人說  我們可以讓她早點上學
Pre-school said, we should think about starting her in school early. . .
蘇菲婭跟你說了嗎
Phina tell you that?
我們會讓她上私立學校
Yeah, we'll put her in private school.
統一的校服
Uniforms.
那天我看了圣B小學
I was looking at Saint B the other day,
他們那里實行西班牙語
and they got this new thing where they start 'em off speaking Spanish,
和英語雙語教學
then they put them back on English...
我不會再來這里
I'm not coming here anymore.
什么
What?
我不會再來監獄看你
I'm not coming here for these visits anymore.
-這是最后一次  -我知道
-This is my last time. -I know, I know. . .
這也是我最后一次犯事
I know, this is the last time for me, too.
我不會再犯事
I told you that. I ain't going down no more.
你讓蘇菲婭承擔這一切而你卻撒手不管
You wanna keep putting Sophina through this, then you go right ahead, OK?
塔蒂阿娜不該經歷這些  奧斯卡
But Tatiana? That baby doesn't deserve this, Oscar.
她還不懂這些
She's too young to know what's going on.
我想這就是為什么她問我
So I guess that's why she asked me why you love
你寧愿度假也不愿陪她
taking your vacations more than you like being with her.
-她不會這么說  -你是說我騙你咯
-She ain't say that. -Oh, so I'm a liar now.
你跟她說我愛她
Ma, you got to tell her I love her.
-跟她說...-你自己跟她說吧
-Tell her I ...-Tell her yourself.
下次你打電話回家自己跟她說
The next time you call home, you tell her yourself.
或者讓她來這里看你
Or better yet, let her come visit you here.
我
Yeah, but I . . .
她不需要知道
She don't need to be exposed. . .
你已經讓她知道了
You already exposed her. . .
-你已經讓她知道了  -這么說你不管我了
-You already exposed her to this. -So what, you gonna leave me?
你打算又不管我  你是什么媽媽
You gonna leave me again? What kind of mom is you?
你打算把我扔在這里不管
You gonna fuck around and leave me in here?
你從沒要我回去
You ain't never had my fuckin' back anyway.
我一個人在這
I'm in here by myself.
-我愛你  奧斯卡  -你什么也不愛
-I love you, Oscar. -You don't love nothin'.
真的
I do.
我為你禱告
And I'm praying for you.
等你出來時再見
I'll see you when you get home.
等等  抱下我好嗎
Hey Ma, hold up. Let me get a hug, Ma?
格蘭特  回到探訪區
Grant,back to the visiting area.
媽媽  對不起  走開
Hey Ma, I'm sorry! Get the fuck out of here!
媽媽  對不起  至少抱下我  至少抱下我
Ma, I'm sorry! At least get a hug! Ma, let me just get a hug!
媽媽  對不起  放開我
Hey Ma, I'm sorry! Get the fuck off me!
放開我  媽媽  對不起
Get the fuck off me! Hey Ma, I'm sorry!
媽媽  對不起  放開我
Ma, I'm sorry! Get the fuck off me!
放開我  媽媽
Get the fuck off me, bruh! Hey, Ma...!
沒想到我們還能再碰面
Shit, bruh. I didn't think we was ever going to hook up.
-怎么了  -我沒事
-What's good? -I'm smooth.
我有好消息和壞消息
I got good news and bad news, though, my nig.
別跟我說你沒拿貨
Don't tell me you ain't got it.
-賣給了一個白人  -真的  多少錢
-Sold it to a white boy. -For real? For how much?
付了我一千塊
Gave me a rack for it.
我不會出這么高價錢
I wasn't gonna pay that high.
盡管我需要  好消息是什么
I still need it, though. What's good?
給你的
For the drive up?
好極了
Right on, Osc.
不用付錢
No, you're good, bruh.
-真的  -收下吧
-You sure? -Take it.
好
Right on.
你要來一根嗎
Burn one with your boy right quick, though.
不用  你抽吧
Nah, it's all you, bruh.
好的  保重
Right on, Osc. All right, bruh. Be smooth.
保重
Yeah.
能馬上送我去奶奶家換衣服嗎
Can you take me to my grandma's house real quick to get changed?
可以
Yeah.
你買的什么蛋糕
What kind of cake you get?
胡蘿卜蛋糕
Carrot cake.
為什么不選冰淇淋的
Why you ain't get ice cream?
又不是你生日
'Cause it ain't your birthday.
如果把你的東西放在我那里就方便多了
You know, it'd be hella easier if you had your stuff at my spot, right?
你為什么不搬過來
Why don't you just move in?
等你接T前不再在車里抽大麻那天
Maybe when you stop blowing trees in the car before we pick up T.
能把車窗搖下來嗎
Can you roll down the window, please?
T  過來
Hey T! T! Come here.
-爸爸  -小家伙
-Daddy! -Hey, what's up, nugget?
孩子
Hey, what's up, girl?
玩得開心嗎
How you doin'?
-開心  -開心
-Good. -Good?
今天我們玩了抓人游戲
We played freeze tag today.
是嗎  你贏了沒
Really? Did you win?
-他們抓不到我  -你一定跑的很快
-They couldn't catch me. -Think you fast, huh?
比爸爸還快
Think you're faster than Daddy?
真的
Mm. Really?
那是什么
What's that?
嘿
Hey!
我打不敗的  我打不敗的
Undefeated! Undefeated!
你還沒打敗我  知道嗎
You still haven't beaten me yet. You know that, right?
-你干什么  -什么意思
-What are you doing? -What do you mean?
-你把車弄壞了  -沒事的
-You're going to break this car! -It'll be all right.
-車都快散架了  -我不能輸  打不敗的
-It's already falling apart. -I can't lose. Undefeated.
爸爸無敵
Daddy's 100 and 0.
大騙子  你這個大騙子
Big, big, big cheater. You're a cheater.
我沒作弊
I didn't cheat.
你怎么知道我作弊
How do you know if I cheated or not?
你剛才在車里  T  你媽媽懷恨在心
You were sitting in the car. T, Mommy's a hater.
-奶奶  -什么事
-Grandma? -Yes?
今晚你能照看下T嗎  我們要去舊金山
Can you watch T tonight? We want to go to 'Frisco.
問你姐姐
Ask your sister.
但是羅斯要照看好幾個孩子
But Rose got hella kids to watch.
照看六個或七個孩子有區別嗎
But what's the difference between watching six kids or watching seven kids?
(西班牙語)
爸爸  你衣服上是什么
Daddy, what's that on your shirt?
爸爸工作時出了點意外
Daddy had an accident at work.
工作的事怎么樣
How is work, by the way?
工作就是工作
Work is...work.
我等下回來
I'll be back.
這件怎么樣
What you think?
挺好看
It's cool.
床上那件衣服是給你的
Put a shirt on the bed for you, if you want.
我換上
Right on.
你沒事吧
Are you all right?
奧斯卡  怎么了
Osc...What's up?
嗯
Hm?
我工作丟了
Fuck it. I lost my job.
為什么
For what?
上班遲到
Being late.
前陣子想掙點錢
Last couple of days, trying to get some money.
他們今天告訴你的
And they told you today? On your day off?
兩個星期前的事了
Can I keep it real? They told me two weeks ago.
我的錯  蘇菲婭
My bad, Phina.
我以為可以要回工作
I thought I was gonna get my job back. . .
你以為生活鬧著玩的嗎
You think life's a fucking joke?
你以為被開除了
You think you're gonna get fired
有人會給你工作嗎
and somebody's gonna give you your job back?
你現在打算怎么辦
What? What game you running now, Osc?
你什么都不是
You ain't shit, you know that?
你對我撒謊  對你自己的女兒撒謊
You lie to me, you lie to your fucking daughter. . .
我不該跟你說的  這樣一切都會照舊
I ain't had to tell your ass nothing. Food on the table, the lights still on.
我應該瞞著你的  你不用知道這些
I could've kept getting it, you wouldn't have known shit.
你打算就這么瞞下去
Oh, so you would've just kept faking?
然后整天在外面混
And been out there bustin' knocks, and doing whatever else,or whoever else. . .
你說你想聽真話
You say you want the truth, right?
你根本不聽我說什么
You ain't even tryin' to hear me. You ain't even trying to hear it.
You ain't even listening to me.
因為你瞞了兩個星期  現在被逼入絕境  沒得選擇
Not after you lie for two weeks, get cornered, and don't have a choice.
這不是男子漢的行為
That's some pussy-ass shit.
你今天干什么了
What'd you do today? Huh?
你肯定去賣大麻了
I bet you sold that fucking zip.
我已經不做了
I dumped that shit, Phina.
我正想告訴你
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
我好累
I'm tired.
以為我可以重新來過
Thought I could start over fresh, but. . .
但事情沒這么順利
. . .shit ain't workin' out.
你沒賣大麻又沒找到工作
You threw a whole zip of weed out and you don't got a job?
我真想扇你
I could slap you right now.
你怎么辦
What are you gonna do?
做些合法的事
Something legal.
也許我可以好好的過30天
Maybe if I could just not fuck up for 30 days.
奧普拉不是說養成一種習慣需要30天嗎
That's how long Oprah said it takes to form a habit, right?
看著我
Look at me.
別再讓我一人承擔這些
Don't make me have to go through this shit alone, again.
脫掉  脫掉
Get this off. Take it off.
"吶"和"哈"的發音明顯不同
A distinct difference between "Nah" and "Haa."
對
Yeah.
你們來的剛好
Hey, you guys are just in time!
生日快樂
Happy birthday!
你們給我買了生日蛋糕
Oh, you guys got me a cake, too?
-生日快樂  -謝謝你  孩子
-Yup. Happy birthday. -Thank you, baby.
好香啊
Smells good in here.
下來
Here you go.
看看你
Look at you. . .
奶奶
Hey Grandma.
什么這么香
What's smelling so good?
奧斯卡
Oh, Osc. . .
你知道我只要兩個  你不用花這么多錢
Baby, you know I only needed two. You didn't have to spend so much money.
媽媽  這個你不用擔心
Mama, you don't gotta worry about that.
-噢  -好吧
-Oh...-OK.
-干嘛呢  -在做壞事
-What's up? -We're up to no good. . .
-你們好嗎  -你好嗎  奧斯卡
-How you guys doing? -How you doin', Oscar?
一切都好嗎  奧斯卡
What's going on, Oscar?
-都挺好的  -真的
-Nothin', hangin' out. -Yeah?
弄點吃的  我餓了
Get some food. I'm hungry.
你拿的什么
Uh-oh, what you got?
給媽媽的卡片
Mom's card.
香蒂讓我替她買張卡片
Tay wanted me to go pick her up one.
-給你  -謝謝
-There you go. -Appreciate that.
她看到這個一定會瘋掉
She's gonna flip out over this one.
-不是吧  -那是香蒂
-Oh, come on, now. -That's Chantay there.
拿東西進來了  把它放在...
We got stuff comin' in. You want to put it in. . .
不能扔掉
You can't dump it!
我這么小的時候她就這樣對我說的
No, that's what she told me when I was this size.
"不能扔掉"
"You can't dump it!"
T  你爸爸像你這么小的時候
You know, T,when your daddy was your size,
他經常跟我和奶奶做這些
just your age, he used to do this with me and grandma.
是的  不過他沒你做的好
Yes, he did, but he didn't do it nearly as well as you're doing it.
沒錯  他洗過的我都得重新洗
No, he did not. I had to re-crack everything he cracked.
蘇菲婭  你們很相愛
Sophina, you are in love, honey.
-是的  -因為他不是大考驗
-I am. -'Cause he was not a great try.
你覺得這屆超級碗哪個隊會贏
Who you think gonna win the Super Bowl?
-鋼人隊  -鋼人隊
-The Steelers. -Steelers?
-是的  鋼人隊  -什么
-Yeah, the Steelers. Yeah. -What?
突擊者的球迷支持鋼人隊
A Raiders fan cheerin' for the Steelers.
Yes, a Raiders fan cheerin' for the Steelers.
黑色隊服  黑人球員  黑人教練
Black uniforms, black players, black coach.
教練的老婆也是黑人  我支持鋼人隊
Coach even has a black wife. I'm going for the Steelers.
你瘋了
You insane!
我知道自己瘋了
I know I'm insane. You know I'm insane?
-開飯啦  -馬上來
-It's ready. -All good!
你不伺候我們
You ain't goin' to serve us?
我從沒伺候過你  塞費斯
I didn't serve you your whole life, Cephus.
開飯啦
OK, get us somethin' to eat!
來段美食舞蹈
Doin' my food dance.
我的盤子呢  旺達
Where my table tray, Wanda?
你的盤子在你房間  達里爾
I got your table tray at your house, Daryl.
塞費斯  剛才是你
Oh, Cephus, that was you?
那是塞費斯  你知道不是我
That was Cephus,you know that wasn't me. . .
不好意思  達里爾  不好意思
I'm sorry, Daryl. I'm sorry.
給你的  孩子  還要加點蟹肉嗎
Here you are, sweetheart. There you go. You want a little more crab?
夠了
I'm good.
謝謝  謝謝
Oh, thanks. Thanks.
-不要這樣  -你們夠了
-None of that. -All right, you all.
大家一起來
All right, everybody.
萬能的主啊
Oh, Heavenly Father,
謝謝你讓我們全家相聚
we thank you for having our family together tonight.
我們很幸運能享受奶奶做的她拿手的湯
We are blessed that Grandma Bonnie made her famous gumbo.
謝謝你賜給我們豐盛的晚餐  阿門
In your name, let's feast. Amen.
阿門
Amen.
-生日快樂  媽媽  -最好的生日禮物
-Happy birthday, Mama. -Best birthday present.
謝謝你今晚幫忙
Thanks for your help tonight.
媽媽  你不用謝我
Come on, Mama. You ain't got to thank me.
我本來就不該讓你做這些
I shouldn't even be letting you do this.
沒事  很輕松
Oh, please. It's relaxing.
你愛說什么就說什么
Yeah, if you say so.
我說的
I say so.
你們今晚有什么安排
You guys got plans for the night?
沒什么重要的事
Yeah, nothing major though.
和伙伴們一起進城
Meet up with the fellas, head out to the city.
你們出去玩還是
You guys going out, out? Or. . .
我們會很低調的
I think we're just gonna be low-key.
看完煙花后也許會去逛逛
Catch the fireworks, probably roll around a little bit after that.
逛逛
Roll around?
放心
It's gonna be cool, though.
再說  蘇菲婭明早還得上班
Chill. Plus, Phina's gotta get up and go to work in the morning anyway.
你們會喝酒嗎
You guys gonna be drinking?
媽媽  他們會喝酒
Mama, they gonna be drinking.
我上次喝酒是什么時候都記不起來了
I haven't had a drink since...I can't even remember.
要不你們坐地鐵去吧
Why don't you take the train out there.
這樣你們就可以喝酒
That way you guys can drink and hang out
出去玩也沒什么好擔心的
and not have to worry about anything.
我們去去就回
Nah, I feel like getting over there and getting back.
-不用做地鐵  -坐地鐵還不堵車
-Not waiting on no train. -No traffic, either.
去和回來的路上一定很堵
You know? You know it's gonna be crazy, going and coming back.
我們也許會坐地鐵
Yeah, we might take it.
別讓我老盯著你們
Don't make me follow you guys to make sure.
記得畢業舞會的事嗎
Remember prom?
正想忘記
Trying to forget.
(發短信給克里斯:我們坐地鐵去吧)
走了  我們得走了
We gotta go. We're gonna go, OK?
親愛的  謝謝你
Honey, thank you.
沒事吧
You good?
-我去拿東西  -說再見了嗎
-Let me get my stuff. -Did you say goodbye?
過來
Come here.
-我們要走了  -我愛你們
-We're outta here. -I love you.
-好的  -不用起來  不用起來
-All right, now. -Don't get up, don't get up.
你們去吧  玩得開心點
All right, so you going out. All right, have fun.
新年快樂
Happy New Year.
好了
All right, all right.
-我愛你  -我也愛你
-Love you. -Love you, too.
-生日快樂  -謝謝你  孩子
-Happy birthday. -Thank you, baby.
-過來  -新年快樂
-Come here. -Happy New Year.
新年快樂
Happy New Year.
我們今晚別去了吧
Let's just call it a night.
我要去
I'm going out.
我不管你干嘛  反正我要去舊金山
I don't know what you're doing, but I want to go into 'Frisco.
我們可以在家觀看新年倒計時活動
We can just watch the countdown from the house.
不行
Mm-mm.
去吧  我想玩玩
Let's go out. I wanna have fun.
喝醉
Get drunk.
好吧
All right.
-我們進城  -真的
-We'll go to the city. -Yeah?
真的
Yeah.
-新年快樂  -新年快樂
-Happy New Year! -Happy New Year!
你們好壯
Oh no! You guys are so strong!
新年快樂
Hi, happy New Year.
別鬧了  奧斯卡  我剛準備讓他們睡覺
Come on, Osc. I just got them ready for bed.
好癢啊  好吧  你贏了
That tickles! All right, you win!
孩子們  讓叔叔起來  快點
Guys, let your uncle up. Come on.
-讓叔叔起來  -你贏了  你贏了
-Let your uncle up. -You win, you win!
快去睡覺
Go to bed. Come on.
去刷牙好嗎
Ready to go brush those teeth?
-不好  -不好
-No. -No?
如果不刷牙  你的牙齒會爛掉
'Cause if you don't, your teeth is going to rot
你的口氣就會像湯飯一樣
and your breath's going to start smelling like gumbo.
-你喜歡這樣嗎  -喜歡
-You want that? -Yes.
-你不會喜歡的  -喜歡
-No, you don't. -Yes.
因為湯飯怪物會來抓你
'Cause then the Gumbo Monster will get you!
爸爸
Daddy!
繼續
Go on.
你也吃了湯飯
You had gumbo, too.
里面的牙齒也要刷
Get those chompers in the back.
下面
Down low.
差點就贏了我
You almost got me.
-哎喲  -怎么了
-Ouchie! -Come on.
我的腳好痛
My feet hurt.
我們要走了
We're getting ready to take off, OK?
你們不在這里過夜嗎
You guys aren't going to sleep over, too?
我們已經答應朋友
We already promised our friends
今晚和他們出去
we was going to kick it with them tonight.
我們會在你起床前回來
But we'll be back before you wake up though, OK?
不要走
No! Don't go.
我害怕
I'm scared.
怕什么
Scared of what?
我聽到外面有槍聲
I hear guns outside.
那些是煙花的聲音
You know what, baby? Those is firecrackers.
你和表兄表姐們在屋里很安全
You're safe inside with your cousins.
那你呢  爸爸
What about you, Daddy?
我
Me?
我沒事
Baby, I'm gonna be fine.
我告訴你
I'll tell you what, though.
你明天起床后  我們玩糖果樂園
When you wake up in the morning, we're gonna play Candy Land.
你猜之后我們會做什么
And then guess what we're gonna do after that.
-去公園  -更好
-Go to the park? -Better.
玩具反斗城
Toys"R"Us?
比那更好玩
Way better than that.
為什么
Why?
查克奶酪游戲屋怎么樣
I don't know, maybe...Chuck E. Cheese?
-真的  -我保證
-Really? -I promise.
爸爸會陪你玩遍所有游戲好嗎
Daddy's gonna give you hecka tokens and we gonna play all the games, OK?
然后去吃你最愛的披薩
And then we're gonna get your favorite pizza,
我們把它全吃光
and we'll eat it all up.
包括媽媽的  因為她要減肥
Even Mommy's ,'cause she can't have carbs.
減肥
What's a carb?
你現在不用擔心這個
You ain't got to worry about that right now.
我愛你
I love you.
我也愛你  爸爸
I love you, too, Daddy.
-索尼婭...-兩個
-Sonja...Nigga, I passed...-Mm-hm. That's two.
我把她攤派給你了
I passed her on to you. I be putting you on her.
我交過的兩只手就數的過來
I can count all of mine on two hands.
奧斯卡人呢
Where the fuck is nigga Oscar at, bruh?
他今天早些時候來找過工作
He came by the job earlier today.
-他總是遲到  -靠
-He's always late, bruh. -Ah, damn, damn. . .
老是圍著蘇菲婭轉
Fuckin' around with Sophina,always, bruh.
這就是男人的墮落
Damn, nigga.That's the downfall of man. . .
女人拖累男人
Bitch slowing a nigga down and shit.
說什么呢  準備走了嗎
Fuck all that shit, y'all niggas ready to go?
嘿
Hey!
我們都在等你
We waitin' on you, nigga!
當然了  她得去梳妝打扮
Of course, it was, man. She had to get her hair and shit and all that.
-你好嗎  -遲到鬼
-You, what up, bruh? -Late-ass, nigga. . .
不能怪我
Hey man, it ain't me!
奧斯卡  為新年來一口
Osc, take a shot for the New Year, nigga!
新年快樂  兄弟們
Happy New Year's, motherfuckers.
新年快樂
Happy New Year to you, too.
我沒買票
I ain't got my ticket.
-嘿  -走吧
-Hey! -Let's go, boys!
快點
Come on, man. . .
趕緊的
Hurry up, bruh.
車門關閉
Doors close.
-新年快樂  -新年快樂
-Hi, happy New Year. -Happy New Year.
請不要毛手毛腳
Make sure you keep your hands to yourself.
在地鐵吸煙可是違法的
Did you know it's illegal to smoke blacks on the BART.
是嗎  警官
Is that right, Officer?
今天是節日  放你們一馬
We're gonna let y'all slide 'cause it's a holiday and all.
口渴嗎  你們要嗎
You thirsty? You guys good?
好極了
Right on, bruh. For sure.
我喜歡你的發型
I like your dreads.
我喜歡你的一切  我們應該在一起
Shit, I like your everything. We need to put it together.
-我們是同性戀  -開什么玩笑
-Oh, we gay. -No shit?
-同性戀  -這么巧
-Gay, huh? -Sounds like a coincidence.
我們也是同性戀
We gay, too.
你們才不是同性戀
You're not gay.
奧斯卡  我們是同性戀嗎
Hey Osc, bruh. Ain't we gay?
徹頭徹尾的同性戀
Yeah, they gay as fuck.
到達西奧克蘭站
Approaching West Oakland Station.
抱歉  各位乘客  列車稍微晚點
Sorry folks,there's gonna be a slight delay.
-我們一定能趕到  -我們趕不到了
-We gonna make it. -No, we're not.
-我們能趕到  -現在幾點
-Yeah, we are. -What time is it?
-別這么消極  -我不是消極
-Stop being so negative. -I'm not being negative.
我們一定能趕到
You know we'll make it.
你好
What's up, bruh?
害我們要錯過倒計時了
They're gonna fuck around and miss the countdown.
我們不會錯過
We ain't gonna miss shit.
我們可以在這里慶祝
We fixin' to get cracked right here.
抱歉  各位乘客  列車繼續前行
Sorry folks.We're back on our way. . .
下一站  蒙哥馬利站
Next stop, Montgomery Station.
有表嗎
Hey gotta watch?
把音樂關掉
Turn the music down, bruh.
10  9  8
Ten, nine, eight,
7  6  5
seven, six, five,
4  3  2  1
four, three, two, one!
新年快樂
Happy New Year!
你要買個新的
You gonna get a fresh one! You gonna get a fresh one!
天啊
Oh, my God!
有人想方便嗎  我得找個地兒方便下
Hey, do you gotta pee? I gotta find somewhere to pee.
你不是剛從洗手間出來
You just left the bathroom.
那里太臟了  我不想在那方便
It's hella dirty in there, I'm not gonna pee in there.
-你一定很冷吧  -我冷死了
-Now you have to be hella cold... -I am hella cold.
你知道怎么做
And you know what's gonna happen.
-我是年輕小伙  -你是個紳士
-A young man right here. -See? You are a gentleman.
他是紳士  這個手提包和你真配
He's a gentleman. That purse looks real good on you, too.
你拿著這個手提包真配
You look real good in that purse.
說什么呢  作為男友  這是我應該做的
What? Look, as a boyfriend, it's what I gotta do.
-我憋不住了  -我知道
-I gotta pee so bad. -I know, I know.
問問這家店
Ask the store right here.
你好  能讓我們用下洗手間嗎
What's up, bruh? You got a bathroom that we could use?
我已經關門了
I'm all closed up, man.
我也沒有供顧客使用的洗手間
And I don't even have a bathroom for my customers.
你一定有供店員使用的洗手間吧
But I'm sure you got a bathroom for your employees, right?
我也沒多少錢  明白我意思嗎
Say, bruh, I ain't rich at all, you feelin' me?
這是我最后十塊錢
Here's my last ten dollars.
要么你收下這十塊  讓他們用下洗手間
Now, you can take this ten, let them use the bathroom,
要么你回家
or you can go home.
等你明天來時  這兒一定到處是小便
When you come back tomorrow, there's gonna be hella piss here
她們總不能尿褲子里吧
'cause they ain't gonna pee on themselves, you feelin' me?
真的
For real?
看看她
Look at her.
-就這兩位女士  -就這兩位女士
-Just these two girls? -Just these two girls.
去吧  小心腳下
OK, come on in. Just watch your step.
謝謝
Thank you.
不用了  新年快樂
Don't worry about it, man. Happy New Year.
新年快樂
Happy New Year.
這兒一定有洗手間吧
Please tell me this place has a bathroom.
怎么了
What?
她懷孕了
She's pregnant.
-進來吧  -謝謝
-OK, come on. -Thank you.
-謝謝你  -不用謝
-Thank you. -No problem.
-不能再來人了  -沒問題
-No more. -That's it.
保證是最后一個
Promise, last one.
-多謝  -不用謝
-Thanks a lot, man. -No problem.
-非常感激  -沒事
-Appreciate that. -Yep.
還以為她只能在大街上解決
Thought she was gonna have to go in the street.
我們也差不多
We almost had the same problem.
你們結婚多久了
How long you guys been married?
八年
Eight years.
你打算結婚
You thinkin' about it?
是什么在阻撓你
What's stopping you?
-沒錢  -很爛的理由
-No money. -Ah, shitty reason.
-我們結婚時一無所有  -開什么玩笑
-We had nothing when we got married. -No shit?
我當時沒工作  她是個老師
I wasn't working at all,and she's a teacher,
不過她掙的錢也不多
it's practically the same thing, as far as money goes.
婚戒哪來的
How'd you get a ring?
我偷的
I stole it.
說了我沒錢  過去靠信用卡過活
Told you, I didn't have any money. Used to be good with credit cards.
-我不想再這樣下去  -我理解
-I would not go down that road. -No, bruh. I'm cool on that.
之后我的生意開始有點起色
Seriously, but then I got my business started,
送了她現在戴著那只戒指
got her the ring she wears now.
-你做哪一行  -網頁設計公司
-What do you do? -Got a Web design company.
如果你有需要就打電話給我
Hit me up if you ever need anything.
-皮特  -沒錯
-Peter? -Yeah.
-奧斯卡  -幸會
-Oscar. -Hi, nice to meet you.
幸會
Nice to meet you too, bruh.
她們出來了
Here they come.
-好了吧  -好了
-You good? -Yeah.
-嗨  -嗨  寶貝兒
-Hi. -Hi, baby.
真高興遇到你們
It was nice meeting you guys.
-恭喜你們  -謝謝
-Congratulations. -Thanks again, man.
-不用謝  -保重
-No problem. -You take care.
新年快樂
Happy New Year, bruh.
-怎么了  -沒事吧
-What up? -We good?
我們走吧
Yeah, man, we gotta get out!
-別廢話了  -走吧
-Now you're talkin' about shit, man. -Let's go.
快點
Come on.
下一站  弗魯特韋爾站
Next stop,Fruitvale Station.
坐下
Sit down.
我沒事  你去找個座位
I'm good, fool. Get a seat.
-確定  -我沒事
-You sure? -I'm good.
我去找個座位
I'm gonna go find a seat.
好的
Sure, bruh.
借過
Excuse me.
嘿  嘿  奧斯卡
Hey! Hey! Oscar!
我是凱蒂
Hey! Katie, from the store.
-嘿  -你好嗎
-Hey, hey! -How are you?
-很好  很好  新年快樂  -新年快樂
-I'm good, I'm good. Happy New Year. -Happy New Year.
奧斯卡  帕爾馬那鬼地方來的
Oscar? Oscar from fuckin' Palma Ceia?
記得你沖我吼的事嗎
What's up with all that shit you were hollerin'?
你媽的  今天別惹我
Look, fuck all that shit, all right? This ain't the time, bruh.
你這個混蛋
Fuck that shit, bitch. This is DGF, motherfucker.
-奧斯卡  什么事  -叫克里斯過來
-Oscar, what's up? -Get Chris for me!
-這里是南海沃市  臭小子  -他們在打奧斯卡
-It's South Hayward, bitch! -They're jumping Oscar!
-弗魯特韋爾站  -南方來的孬種
-Fruitvale Station. -Punk-ass Southside niggas. . .
去他媽的
Fuck them niggas.
列車上有人打架
There's been an incident on the train.
大家冷靜  警察馬上就來
Stay calm , the police are on their way.
請大家保持冷靜  警察馬上就來
Please remain calm ,the police are on their way.
我們趕緊下車吧
Better get the fuck off this train, bruh.
警察來了  快回到車上去
The police, baby.Get back on the train now.
海沃德見  兄弟們  大家分開走
Meet me in Hayward. Hey boys, div up. Split up, bruh.
明白嗎
You feel me?
你們三個到墻邊去
You three, to the wall.
-把手拿出來  -你們兩個  快點
-Get your hands out of your pockets. -You two, let's go.
把手拿出來  面對著墻
Get your hands out of your pockets. Against the wall.
-快過去  -你說什么
-Get over there! -Man, what you talkin' about?
美女  讓這位警官冷靜點
Hey sexy, tell this brute to calm the fuck down.
-好像不是真的警察  -蹲下
-Wow. Like that ain't real police. -Get down.
要不是你戴著徽章  我絕不客氣
If you ain't had that motherfuckin' badge, bruh, it'd be on, straight up.
參與打架的人馬上下車
If you were involved in the fight, get off the fuckin' train now!
別逼我進去揪你出來
Don't make me come in there and pull you off!
-你  下車  -去你的  我什么也沒干
-You, off the train. -Fuck you. I ain't doing shit.
-過來  -干什么
-Get over here. -What the fuck?
-干什么  -全部蹲下
-All right, bruh. -Sit down with your girlfriends.
-我聽到了  我什么也沒干  -冷靜點
-I hear you. I didn't do it, bruh. -Damn, be cool, man.
你要逮捕我們嗎  我們什么也沒干
You arrestin' us? 'Cause we ain't do shit.
憑什么扣留我們
What the fuck, you just gonna hold us?
我一直這么解釋
That's what I've been sayin' this whole time,
但這個美臀警察就是不聽
but she don't want to listen with her cute ass.
-閉嘴  -你打黑人
-Shut up! -Damn, kick a nigga. . .
你的同黨呢
Where are your friends at, huh?
-我們沒同黨  -沒同黨
-We ain't got no friends. -Got no friends. . .
我不知道你在說什么
I don't know what friends you talkin' about.
我看到了一個龐克族
I see one of those punks right now.
站臺需要支援
On the platform in need of backup.
沒事的  兄弟  沒事的
Whoa, it's cool, bruh. It's cool, it's cool.
冷靜  大家冷靜
Chill out, just chill, chill. . .
蹲下  蹲回去
Stay down! Back up! Sit the fuck down!
冷靜點  冷靜點
Be cool, man! Be cool!
別打他
Hey, don't be slammin' my man!
-坐下  坐下  -好的  冷靜點
-Sit down! Sit down! -All right, be cool!
你沒事吧  你沒事吧
You good? You good?
你們不能這樣
You all can't do no shit like that!
-蹲下  -冷靜  冷靜
-Back down! -Be cool, be cool!
別碰他
Hey, don't fuckin' touch him!
-你干什么  -趴下
-What the fuck is that about, man? -Get yourself on the ground.
-趴下  -你想打我
-Get on the ground! -You want to sucker punch me like that?
-去你的  -龐克豬
-Fuck that, bruh! -Punk-ass pig!
-你沒事吧  -沒事
-You all right? -Yeah, I'm good.
-你要干嘛  -看你們要干什么
-What is wrong with you? -All right, OK. S'up.
退回去  退回去  退回去
Back up! Back up! Get back!
我拿著手機就要電擊我嗎
You gonna tase me if I have my phone?
我已經拍下了你的工號
Yeah, I got your badge number, bruh.
閉嘴  手機收起來
Shut the fuck up and put that phone away!
沒問題  你怕什么
Yeah, all right. But why? What you trying to hide, bruh?
看好這些混蛋  我去車上找目擊者
You keep these assholes secured, I'm gonna check the train for witnesses.
-混蛋警察  -我拍到你了
-Punk motherfuckers. Badge...-I got you.
-手機收起來  -我們走吧
-Put the fuckin' phone away. -Get the fuck out of here, bruh.
媽的  簡直亂來
Fuck these, niggas. This is bullshit.
-沒事吧  -我沒事  我沒事
-Cool, bruh? -I'm good, I'm good.
我們沒事的  我沒事
We're gonna be good. I'm good.
-閉嘴  -蘇菲婭  怎么了
-Shut up. -Phina, what's up?
-你還在車上嗎  -沒有  我們還在弗魯特韋爾站
-Where you at? You still on the train? -Hell no, we still at Fruitvale.
他們扣留了我們并且打我們
They holding us and beating on us and shit.
-誰打你  -警察
-Who the fuck is beating on you? -The fuckin' police.
-別打電話  -我等下就過來
-Get off your phone! -I'm gonna get us out of here.
-待會兒見  -奧斯卡
-I'll meet you back, OK? -Osc!
-我愛你  -這些混蛋警察
-I love you. -These bitch-ass police.
沒事  我們沒事的
It's cool, bruh. I'm gonna get us up outta here.
-坐下  坐下  -聽我說
-Sit down, sit down! -Let me talk with you. . .
給我坐下
Sit the fuck down.
-天啊  -別這樣
-Jesus...-Hey, come on, man.
-干什么  -坐下
-Fuck this bullshit! -Sit!
沒事  別怕  我們沒事  我們沒事
It's cool. You know what, man? We good, bruh. We good, bruh.
隨便他們扣留多久
They can hold us as long as they want,
他們不能無緣無故逮捕我們
but they can't arrest us 'cause we ain't do shit.
-你說什么  -我說我們什么也沒干
-What's that? -I say we ain't do shit!
-你們不能逮捕我們  -是嗎
-Y'all can't fuckin' arrest us. -Oh yeah?
把這兩個銬起來  等著坐牢吧
Cuff these two assholes, they're going to jail.
-干嘛  你不能逮捕我們  -這下滿意了
-Fuckin' what! You can't arrest us! -How about that?
-跪下  -你不能逮捕我
-Get on your knees. -You can't fuckin' arrest me!
快跪下
Knees, now!
我只是要回家
I'm just tryin' to get home, bruh!
我們不該進監獄
We ain't tryin' to go to jail, you feel me?
我們只是要回家
We just tryin' to get home. We just tryin' to get home. . .
也許你剛才就該好好想想
Maybe you should've thought about that,
而不是像個龐克豬一樣
before you started acting like a punk-ass bitch.
你不能罵他
Don't call my partner no bitch.
你這個混蛋警察
You's a bitch-ass nigger, for real.
叫我"混蛋警察"
Did you call me a "bitch-ass nigger"?
-別亂說  -混蛋黑鬼
-Don't fuckin' say that. -Bitch-ass nigger, huh?
憑什么  我什么也沒干
What the fuck! I ain't do shit!
操
Fuck!
我扳不動他的手
I can't get his fucking arm!
-手翻過來  -你壓到我的頭了
-Roll over! -You're on my head, man!
手翻過來
Roll over!
你竟然開槍打我
You fuckin'...You fuckin' shot me, bruh.
你開槍打我  我還有個女兒
You shot me. I got a daughter.
起來
Get up, bruh!
-把他拉開  -他什么也沒干
-Get him out! -He didn't do nothing!
-快點  -奧斯卡  起來
-Go! Go! -Oscar, get up, bruh!
叫救護車  他快死了
Call an ambulance! Man, he's dying, man!
快開車
Get this train out of here!
-退后  -干什么
-Back up! -What the fuck!
快走
Get out of here.
快開車
Get the train out of here, now!
快
Move!
為什么車還不開走
Why isn't this train moving!
-你干嘛  -快走
-What did you do?! -Let's go!
進去
Get in there!
弗魯特韋爾站發生槍擊  代號3  請求醫療支援
Shots fired, Fruitvale. Code 3.Stage fire and medical.
你在想什么
What the fuck happened?
啊
Huh?
看著我  看著我好嗎
Look at me. Can you look at me?
-他向我開槍  -你堅持住
-He shot me. -You stay right here.
我還有一個女兒
Shot me...I got a...a daughter.
別閉上眼睛
Keep your eyes open.
操
Fuck.
快接啊
Come on, talk.
蘇菲婭
Sophina?
警察抓了奧斯卡他們
The police, they got Oscar and them.
我聽見有動靜  不知道是不是槍聲
I heard something and I don't know if it was a beanbag. . .
蘇菲婭  冷靜  我沒聽清你說什么
Sophina, honey, calm down. I can't hear you.
奧斯卡和你在一起嗎
Is Oscar there with you?
沒有  他和警察在站臺上面
No, he's upstairs with the police.
我們現在想上去找他們
But we're downstairs and we're trying to get up to them,
-但警察不讓我們上去  -奧斯卡被抓了嗎
-and they're not letting us upstairs. -Did Oscar get arrested?
不清楚  我估計是
I don't know, but I think so, Wanda.
我等下再打給你
OK, I'm gonna call you back.
那是誰
Who's that for?
-請問那是誰  -讓開
-Sorry, who's that for? -Stay back.
那是誰  那是誰
Who's that for? Who is that for?
為什么不告訴我發生了什么事
Why can't you tell me what is going on?
到底怎么了  告訴我怎么回事
What is the problem? Tell me what's going on?
賈森  賈森  怎么回事  怎么回事
Jason! Jason! What happened? What happened!
-警察向他開槍  -怎么回事
-They fuckin' shot him! -What happened?
警察無緣無故向奧斯卡背部開槍
They shot Oscar in his fuckin' back for no reason, man!
他人呢  奧斯卡在哪
Where is he? Where is Oscar! Where is he?
奧斯卡在哪
Where is Oscar? Where is he!
到底怎么了
What is going on?
他在哪
Where is he?
奧斯卡  能聽到嗎
Oscar, can you hear me?
我還有個女兒
I have a daughter. . .
粘好  套上
Tape here. Bag him.
-求求你  -你感覺如何
-Please...-That's how you feel?
我男朋友在上面
My boyfriend is...My boyfriend is up there, OK?
你不明白
You don't understand. Please. . .
我男朋友在上面
Please, my boyfriend is up there, OK?
-請讓我上去  -你要向我們開槍嗎
-You need to let me up there. -Y'all gonna shoot us too?
-旺達  -蘇菲婭
-Wanda...-Sophina. . .
我想上去  但警察就是不讓
Yeah, been trying to get up there, and they're not letting me up.
-奧斯卡人呢  -天啊  天啊
-Where's Oscar? -Oh, my God...Oh, my God.
你們把他怎么了
What did you do to him?
你們殺了他  你們把他怎么了
Did you fucking kill him! What did you do to him?
交給我們  卡洛斯  我們會處理
We have it, Carlos. Don't worry, we'll take care of it.
你現在沒事了
You're all right now.
我要確定他沒事
I need to make sure that he's OK!
他是我孩子的父親
That's my fucking baby's daddy right there!
我要和他待著
OK, I need to be next to him!
你們帶他去哪
Where y'all taking him?
-你們帶他去哪  -去高地醫院
-Where are you taking him? -He's going to Highland.
放開我
Get off me!
旺達  警察向奧斯卡開槍
Wanda, they shot Oscar.
警察說他還活著  但是眼睛睜不開了
They say he's alive, but his eyes was closed.
他們帶他去高地醫院  你馬上來接我們
They're taking him to Highland, you gotta come get us right now.
-我馬上來  -操
-I'm on my way. -Oh, fuck.
傷者情況
What do you got for me?
22歲男性  后肩胛骨中槍
Twenty-two year old male, posterior scapula GSW.
中槍時臉朝下躺著  倒數三聲  一  二  三
He was lying face-down when he was shot. On three. One, two, three.
-血壓多少  -收縮壓70
-What was his blood pressure? -Seventy systolic.
-事發時他四肢在動嗎  -是的  手臂和大腿
-Was he moving his limbs? -Yes. Moving arms and legs.
給我一根胸管
I'm gonna need a chest tube.
我們得馬上送他上去
We gotta get him upstairs right away.
你好  我兒子叫奧斯卡·朱利葉斯·格蘭特三世
Excuse me, my son is Oscar Julius Grant III .
他中槍了  警察讓我過來
He's been shot and they told me to come here.
-格什么  -格蘭特
-G-R...-A-N-T, yes.
他在手術  去重癥監護室
OK, he's in surgery. Go to the ICU room. . .
-怎么走  -在那邊
-And that is where? -Right over there.
天啊  希望他沒事
Oh Lord, please let him be safe.
準備輸血
Get that blood in.
剪刀
Scissors.
吸管
Suction.
嘿
Hey.
-嘿  -有消息嗎
-Hey. -Any news?
還沒消息
No, no news yet.
-混蛋  -嘿嘿嘿
-Motherfuckers...-Hey, hey, hey.
別鬧事
Hey, no. Listen, none of that.
別鬧事  別在這里惹事
None of that. This is not the time or the place.
明白嗎
OK?
怎么一點消息也沒有
Why ain't they said nothin' yet?
我們等吧
We waitin'.
別擔心
Come on.
我們要對他有信心
Hey, we gotta keep him positive.
讓他們各司其職
We gotta let these people do their jobs.
他沒事的
He's gonna be fine.
現在把所有精力都放奧斯卡身上
Let's put all our energy towards Oscar right now.
我知道你們很憤怒  但是我們必須給他打氣
I know y'all are upset, but we got to lift him up.
我們必須給他打氣
Let's keep him lifted up.
-我不知道  -沒事的
-I don't know. -It's OK.
-我感覺不好  -冷靜點
-I feel, I feel weird...-Come on man, calm down.
你們聽到媽媽的話了
Y'all heard Mom.
-賈森太太  -什么事
-Ms. Johnson? -Yes?
-醫生有話跟你說  -他怎么樣
-The doctor's going to speak to you. -How is he?
賈森  你也知道你兒子中槍
Ms. Johnson, as you know, your son's been shot.
我們在全力搶救  不過他很危險
Now, we stabilized him, but he's critical.
危險  什么意思
Critical, what is that?
他大量內出血
Well, he has massive internal bleeding,
我們必須切除他的右肺
and we had to remove the right lung.
切肺  那他以后怎么呼吸
His lung? How...how's he going to be able to breathe?
他現在靠呼吸機
He's on a breathing machine right now.
他的呼吸很穩定
So, his breathing is stable.
主要的問題是內出血
The main problem is the internal bleeding.
操
Damn. . .
我們很難讓血止住
Now, we've had some difficulty stopping the bleeding,and getting his blood to clot.
還在觀察他的輸血反應
He hasn't fully responded to the transfusions yet.
他一定會沒事的對嗎
But he's gonna make it, right? He's gonna make it?
我向你保證我們會盡全力
I promise you we're going to do everything possible. . .
安靜
Hey! Hey!
-求求你  -我們會盡全力
-Please...-We'll do what we can.
求求你們盡全力
Please do what you can.
救不活奧斯卡別出來
Don't come back out here without Osc, nigga.
一定要救救他  救救奧斯卡
Bring him out, man. Bring Osc out.
我們得給他打氣
We gotta lift him up, y'all.
我們要給奧斯卡打氣
We got to lift Oscar up.
我不敢相信事情會這樣
I can't even believe this, man, we here, bruh.
-我知道  -我不敢相信
-I know. -I can't believe this.
他是個斗士
Y'all know he's a fighter, man.
-他會挺過來  -混蛋警察
-He'll make it. -Bitch-ass police.
他一定會沒事
He's gonna be all right.
大家都來祈禱
Y'all, let's pray.
都來祈禱
Let's pray.
萬能的主啊
Heavenly Father
我們向你屈膝
we kneel before you
希望你向這個孩子伸出援手
and ask you to put healing hands around your child.
我們請求你賜予這些醫生力量
We ask you, dear Lord, to operate through these doctors.
賜予他們雙手力量去救他
Breathe strength 委nto the委r hands, Lord, as they work on h委m .
我們請求你救活他
We're ask委ng you r委ght now to heal h委m .
救活他  萬能的主
Oh, heal him , dear Lord.
讓我們能重見他的笑顏
So we can hold h委m and see h委s sm委le aga委n.
以你之名  阿門
ln your name, we pray. Amen.
他一定會沒事
He's gonna be all right.
他沒能挺過來
He didn't make it.
我要看看他
I need to see him.
你可以看看他
OK, you can see him.
不過你不能進房間或者碰他
But they don't want you to go into the room or touch him,
因為他們認為這是兇殺
because they ruled it a homicide.
我要看看他
I need to see him.
-我帶她進去  -好吧
-I can take her. -OK.
要我陪你去嗎
You want me to go with you?
不用
No.
不用  他是我的兒子
No, that's my baby.
是我讓他坐地鐵
I told him to take the train.
I told him to catch the BART.
我沒想到事情會這樣
I didn't know they were going to hurt my baby.
我應該讓他開車去
I should've just let him drive.
我應該讓他開車去  我只想他沒事
I should've just let him drive, but I wanted to keep him safe.
讓我進去抱抱他
You gotta let me hug him.
求求你  讓我抱抱他
Please, let me hug him.
求求你
Please. Please. . .
他不想孤單一人
He didn't like to be alone.
起來  T  起來
Come on, T.Come on, baby.
我們得走了
We got to go.
要走了
You got to go?
回去睡覺
Shh. Go back to bed.
Go back to bed, OK? OK. . .
爸爸呢
Where's Daddy?
有目擊者用他們的手機拍下了  弗魯特韋爾地鐵站的這場槍擊事件
這段視頻在舊金山灣區引發一系列抗議和騷亂
涉事警察被開除  舊金山灣區地鐵警察相關負責人辭職
槍殺奧斯卡警察被逮捕并被控一級謀殺罪
涉事警察聲稱他誤把手槍當成電擊槍
陪審團認定他犯有過失殺人罪
被判在州監獄服刑2年  并于服刑11個月后釋放
奧斯卡·朱利葉斯·格蘭特三世
弗魯特韋爾車站  加州  奧克蘭
(為奧斯卡·格蘭特伸張正義)
塔蒂阿娜·格蘭特
安息吧  奧斯卡·格蘭特